Oshino! Why is Black Hanekawa back?
I thought we sealed it away for good during Golden Week.
I never said that.
Didn't I tell you? In the end, the meddlesome cat was just her impetus. Ther real problem is Prez's stress.
Last time, she was able to let stress off just going wild like that.
Se we sealed it away. But it's not gone.
If she builds up too much stress, it'll come back out.
Stress, huh...
Seems like she has a bell around her neck.
That does the trick.
That's how you catch the meddlesome cat early.
What is that bell?
Her headaches.
Prez was complaining about her headaches around Golden Week too, right?
Taking that into account, it's like she was trying to lead you straight to it.
That's why she could only tell you.
Anyway, the problem is stress.
That means it's a matter of what's causing that stress.
Her family just like before, right?
I wonder about that.
She held that stress in for seventeen years.
It just cleared up. Could it really get that bad again this quick?
Even if we've got the reason, neither you nor I can do anything about it.
I don't think we have any option but to treat the symptoms when they pop up.
Yeah. You're right about that, but-
What's wrong, Oshino? You're being vague.
Well, Prez does look pretty good in cat ears.
Reminds me of "Neko Neko Fantasia".
You read it? It was drawn by Nekobe Neko.
Nekobe Neko drew Goldfish Warning, not that!
Come on, Oshino, are you trying to trick me?
Why don't you bring out Shinobu?
We're up against a stupid cat. It's not like we have any options but her.
Yeah, I guess. But, it never rains. It pours.
Bad luck brings along its friends.
Hey, knock it off, Oshi-
Oshino. There's something I want to ask you.
What a coincidence. There's something I've wanted you to ask me.
What happened to Shinobu?
That's it. Shinobu-chan left on a journey to find herself.
She's just a kid. She can't have gone very far.
Plus, she's not like a vampire out of the legends anymore.
If I'm not near her, she's even weaker than a kid.
Even if she went to Mister Donut, she doesn't have a cent to her name.
Maybe she's hungry.
She's somewhere in this city, alone...
Arraragi-san!
Finally, just a typo...
Sorry, I stuttered.
No, it was on purpose!
Wait, I don't have time for this.
Got it. I'll try as hard as I can to find her.
You sure?
Of course, Araragi-san. Finding a lost child requires a lot of careful attention.
If you try to do it all yourself, it's like finding a mummy in a pyramid.
A pyramid? That big?!
Koyomi-oniichan! You called me?
I'm so happy.
What's going on, Koyomi-oniichan?
Well, umm...
Calm down. Did something happen?
Well, yeah, something's up.
Just calm down, Koyomi-oniichan. I know, I'll tell you a funny story.
Well... People in comics and anime seem to have it really easy,
but being a maid must be incredibly stressful work.
Who the hell are you, "the Big Bear Cat lover"?
Are you feeling calmer now, Koyomi-oniichan?
Yeah, hearing that again calmed me down somehow.
Sengoku, I want you to look for Shinobu.
Look for her? You mean she's gone?
Err, Shinobu-chan, that is.
Yeah. She's been gone since yesterday.
Really? Okay, got it.
Just keep in mind that she's still a vampire, even if she's weak.
That's okay, I'll be fine. Leave it to me.
This is Kanbaru Suruga!
I'm Kanbaru Suruga. My specialty is the B-dash.
I'm Kanbaru Suruga. Currently employed as Araragi-senpai's love slave.
That's a complete and total lie!
That voice, that retort. It has to be Araragi-senpai.
Of course. Anyway, Kanbaru, are you at home?
Wow, it's not like you to guess wrong.
Nah, I'm at the supermarket's arcade machines playing "Chic Witches: Love and Berry".
How the hell am I supposed to guess that?!
I've blown almost three thousand yen on it today.
There's tons of kids lined up behind me, but I don't feel like letting them play.
Quit always fooling around!
I mustn't lose my sense of play.
While we're talking about playing, lately, when I've played President with my friends...
What? You were "the Posturing Waggler"?!
Kanbaru. I need your help.
Shinobu ran away from home.
A runaway? Got it.
That's all you need to tell me.
That means I should strip, right?
Anyway, you want me to look for that cute blonde girl, right?
Gotcha.
I'm not going anywhere.
Come on, Senjougahara. Just listen to me.
No, you listen to me.
Yesterday a friend and I went to a video rental place.
You're "Walk toward the apple"?!
Shinobu's gone. I'd like you to help find her.
Does this have anything to do with Hanekawa-san not coming to school?
Yeah, it does.
Hanekawa's-
Oshino-san said last time there was a problem with Hanekawa-san, that Shinobu girl worked really hard.
So that's how it is.
You need her power for Hanekawa-san, but she's gone missing.
Good guess.
You must be worried about both of them very much.
It's obvious you should put one before the other, but not doing so is very much like you.
What's that supposed to mean?
I'm not going anywhere.
Come on, Senjougahara.
I'm busy preparing for the school festival.
I know, but right now-
Hanekawa-san told me to.
I can't just abandon it.
The worse off Hanekawa-san is, the more important it is that I do this for her.
You should do what you have to, just like usual.
And I'll do what I have to.
You're right.
All right, school's your problem. Let's have a great school festival.
Yeah. I hope we do.
Anyway, I'll keep in touch.
Oh, by the the way, Araragi-kun. Can I tell you one thing?
What?
Tsundere service.
Don't get me wrong. It's not like I'm worried about you.
But if you don't come back I'll never forgive you.
Come on. Of course I'm coming back.
That takes a load off my back.
Anyway, I've called in as much help as I can.
Araragi-kun!
What's he doing?
Shinobu. Oshino Shinobu.
I'm gonna find her. I have to.
I'm responsible for you for the rest of my life.
Why are you here?
Purrr.
Answer me!
Don't talk to me like that, humyan. Purrr.
Acting all cute isn't going to get you anywhere.
Weren't you tied up, anyway?
Yeah, but if I feel like stirring up more trouble I can just let myself loose.
How'd you sneak by Oshino?
I'm a cat. Moving without making noise is like taking candy from a baby, meow.
Now that you mention it...
Oshino, you've been pretty useless this time around.
You let Shinobu and Black Hanekawa get away. That's not like you.
Hey, cat.
What is it, meow?
Repeat after me, cat.
Can you imagine an imaginary menagerie manager
imagining managing an imaginary menagerie?
Can mew imyagine an imyaginyary mewnyagerie mewnyager imyagining mewnyaging an imyaginyary mewnyagerie?
So damn cute!
Wait, never mind that. I asked you, why are you here?
What, is that how you say hi?
I came to help you out, humyan.
Help me?
Don't get me wrong, humyan. I don't feel like fighting you anymore.
Didn't I tell you that before, meow?
Before? You mean this morning at school?
Did you tell me that?
Well, maybe I didn't. But it doesn't myatter, I'm telling you now.
I don't feel like going wild this time. That's not what I'm tense about, meow.
Then why are you here? You're a reflection of Hanekawa's stress.
You appeared so Hanekawa could let some of that stress off.
You're like another personality of hers.
Don't misunderstand, meow. This is my way of thanking you.
After all, my myaster was able to work through as much stress in those nine days as she normally could in a year.
Wait, you mean you're on my side?
I see. You're better off the sooner we find Shinobu too.
That's right, meow!
All right, you can lend a hand.
Nyahaha. Is this what they mean by "gold coins to a cyat"?
My Hanekawa would never be so amused by that bad of a joke!
You can help with your sense of smell and hearing. You know Shinobu's voice and scent, right?
We should follow her that way.
Got it.
Okay, I'll drive. If you notice anything, tell me.
What's wrong, humyan?
I forgot about her energy drain.
Let's see if I can get away with saying it.
I, Araragi, do not regret this!
Oh, I see. Humyan, my myaster's boobs felt so great that you fainted?
I may be dumb, but you're a moron.
You don't realize your own power, do you?
Should I really be counting on her?
It's gotten too dark for a human to spot Shinobu.
Show me what you've got.
Oh, you want to see? Nyahaha.
Hey, humyan.
What do you want me to do now?
I'm really not sure I should be counting on her.
Hey, human.
What, stupid cat?
Seems like you went through a lot after the last time you took me on.
With us aberrations.
What, Oshino told you about that?
Yeah. There was a crab, and a snail, and a monkey, and a snake.
Wait, a nue?!
Don't just react to the monkey and snake. Where are the crab and snail parts on one of those?
Anyway, don't just spout off whatever you think up.
And now I'm a vampire.
So, humyan, what do you think of us?
Of what you call "aberrations"?
What do I think of you?
If you think you're going to just get along with us, you've bitten off more than you can chew.
An aberration is an aberration. A humyan is a humyan.
They cyan't be together. No myatter what, they're incompyatible.
I don't get it. What are you trying to tell me?
If you don't get it, it's your own fault for being so dumb, meow.
You of all people saying that is really scarring.
So this is the scarred... Hm, what was it?
So what you mean is that I'll never be able to get along with aberrations?
It sure seems that way.
No, that's not what I'm trying to say, meow.
For example. Have you considered why that vyampire ran off?
No clue.
See? That's how little you really know about us.
That's purrobably why the guy in the Hawaiian shirt's guesses end up being right.
After all, he's at least polite.
Polite?
He knows his place.
We must be...
believed in,
feared,
be afraid of,
avoided,
respected,
worshiped,
hated,
despised,
and receive wishes.
That's why we exist, meow.
Getting along with us is pointless. Approaching us as a friend is just annoying, meow.
Wait, you said that's why you exist, right?
So by treating Shinobu like a little girl, I destroyed Shinobu as an aberration?
Purrhaps, purrhaps not.
I haven't thought it through that much.
Anyway, I can't smell her at all.
You can't smell Shinobu?
Can you tell me just how many of her powers that vyampire can still manifest, humyan?
If she can still appear and disappear, or turn into a shadow, I won't be able to find her.
She can't really manifest any. They only work when I'm around her.
If I'm not there, she's just a ki-
Anyway, humyan. Don't you think it's going to take a bit more effort to find that vyampire?
But she can't be outside the city. Right now, she can't exist that far away from me.
A vyampire drinks blood, right?
A vyampire drinks human blood. But drinking it for a meal and making a follower are purretty different.
I know.
Maybe that's exactly why she ran away, meow.
What do you mean?
You're really dense.
What do you mean, dense?
She couldn't have enjoyed watching you get involved with so many of us without even a break.
You mean she feels less special being held up against all of you?
That's why she couldn't stand staying there?
Dense.
What are you going to do if you don't find her, anyway?
What do you mean? I'm screwed.
Hanekawa won't go back to normal, either.
Except for what's going on with my myaster, purrhaps you'd be better off without the vyampire?
After all, with her gone, you can go back to being humyan.
I can't just let her go!
I don't even care if she kills me.
That's all I know. If she dies tomorrow, I may as well die too.
I see.
Hey, humyan. There's a way to bottle me byack up without relying on a vyampire.
There is?
I'm the purrsonification of my myaster's stress.
If the source of my myaster's stress is dealt with, I'll go away again.
Oshino thought of that too, but I can't figure out what's stressing her.
I told you, I'm its purrsonification.
I know exactly what's causing it.
Really?
And you of all people can deal with it easily.
Easily?
Easy as pie.
My myaster is so dirty.
She loves you, meow.
So if you fall in love with my myaster, I think that might bottle me up.
I'm Karen!
I'm Tsukihi!
Onii-chan's kind of-
What's up with onii-chan?
Isn't it amazing how few friends he has?
Yeah, it's amazing.
But we shouldn't make a point of it.
Then let's not talk about it.
Not having friends isn't lonely!
Not having friends is lonely.
Fine, then let's put loneliness positively!
How are you going to do that?
He's a soloist.
Soloist?!
That makes loneliness sound better.
No, it makes being a soloist sound worse.
Preview quiz!
Quiz!
You think they're a friend, but are they really?
That's scary!
Next time, final episode!
Tsubasa Cat part five.
Maybe they really are a friend.
That's even scarier!